Heroes so small they have to be seen on the big screen.
The Meerkats is a documentary, tv movie, family
film directed by James Honeyborne.
A coming of age story following a young meerkat pup, Kolo, growing up in the Kalahari desert; and an inspiring look at how one
family's connection to each other and their surroundings is a model of resilience and fortitude for us all.
Shot using ground-breaking techniques, this dramatised documentary is a one-of-a-kind
presentation from The Weinstein Company and the BBC, featuring narration by Paul Newman.
Narrator (voice), played by Paul Newman.
Narrator (Russian release) (voice), played by Rufus Beck.
Le narrateur (voix française), played by Guillaume Canet.
The Meerkats, also known as Meerkats: The Movie, is a feature-length 2008 British wildlife fiction film
which anthropomorphises the daily struggles of a clan of meerkats in the Kalahari Desert.
It was produced by BBC Films, and filmed by the
award-winning BBC Natural History Unit.
It is the debut directorial feature of James Honeyborne, previously a
producer of natural history programmes for television.
The worldwide premiere was held at the Dinard Film Festival, France in
October 2008, expanding to a wide release the following week.
The film was released in 2009, on 7 August in the UK.
The film was dedicated to Paul Newman, the narrator of the film, who died in 2008,
shortly before this film was released making it his final film role.
The film explores themes of meerkat, kalahari desert,
animal life, animal behaviour, documentary.
The tone is uplifting.